<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the King an abstract of the seuerall heads and branches of His Maiesties commission of grace, for the securing, setling, and confirming to his subiects their defectiue titles, estates and possessions, by which His Maiesties commissioners haue power to compound.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1625-1649 : Charles I)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1628</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A22492</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 8910</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S122745</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">38159596</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 38159596</idno>
            <idno type="VID">29192</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A22492)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 29192)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1924:6)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the King an abstract of the seuerall heads and branches of His Maiesties commission of grace, for the securing, setling, and confirming to his subiects their defectiue titles, estates and possessions, by which His Maiesties commissioners haue power to compound.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1625-1649 : Charles I)</author>
                  <author>Charles I, King of England, 1600-1649.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>By Bonham Norton and Iohn Bill, Printers to the Kings most Excellent Maiestie,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Imprinted at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Anno M.DC.XXVIII [1628]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Land tenure --  Law and legislation --  Great Britain --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Copyhold --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Charles I, 1625-1649.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-12</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-12</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:29192:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 2 -->
            <head>
               <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> By the King.</head>
            <head type="sub">¶ An Abſtract of the ſeuerall Heads and Branches of His Maie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties Commiſsion of grace, for the ſecuring, ſetling, and confirming to His Subiects their defectiue Titles, Eſtates and Poſſeſsions; By which His Maieſties Commiſsio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners haue power to Compound.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">F</seg>Or all Mannours, Lands, Tenements, Waſtes, Commons, Tithes, ariſing aſwel without any Pariſhes, as within Pariſhes, Liberties, Priuiledges, and other Here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditaments, in the ſaid Commiſſion mentioned, held vnder colour of any defectiue, voide, or inſufficient Grant, or Letters Patents of Concealements, procured out of the Crowne, or otherwiſe meerely intruded vpon, and vſurped without any Grant thereof at all from his Maieſtie, or any of his Predeceſſors.</p>
            <p>All Mannours, Lands, Tenements, and other the premiſſes inſufficiently granted out of the Crowne Intaile, whereof the eſtate taile is not ſpent, or which haue, or ought to haue deſcended vpon the Kings Perſon, or any of his Progenitors, and are inſufficiently granted out of the Crowne, or being formerly granted Intaile, the eſtate taile is ſpent and determined, and ought to reuert vnto the Crowne.</p>
            <p>All Meſſuages and Cottages built, and Incloſures made, vpon the common High wayes, Streetes, Paſſages, Waſtes and Commons.</p>
            <p>All Lands formerly recouered, or deſerted from the Sea, or now ſurrounded with the Sea, and which hereafter may, or ſhall be recouered, or deſerted from the Sea.</p>
            <p>Diuers Paſtures and Grounds adiacent to his Maieſties Forreſts and Parkes, and yet are no parcell of the ſaid Forreſts or Parkes, but purchaſed or vſed by his Maieſtie for the vſe of his Deere, which ſayd Forreſts and Parkes being diſafforreſted, and diſparked, and the Deere de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroyed, the premiſſes are carried away, without any grant thereof from the Crowne.</p>
            <p>All Mannours, Lands, Tenements, and other the premiſſes, which ought to bee in charge, and are not, but ſome Fee-Farme Rent anſwered, as if there were no more due vnto His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ieſtie, whereas, in trueth, the Land it ſelfe belongeth vnto the Crowne, or ſuch Lands, and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther the premiſſes, where both the Lands and Rents ſtand in charge, and the Rent anſwered, and yet the parties ſo enioying the ſayd Lands, neuer had any Grant thereof from the Crowne, or ſuch Lands, and other the premiſſes where the Lands ſtand in charge, as Lands, and yet the Rents ſtand not in charge, nor haue beene anſwered vnto the Crowne by them that pretend Intereſt in the ſayd Lands.</p>
            <p>The Commiſſioners to ſell any of the premiſſes (which are not ſetled by the a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid Act) in Fee-Simple, Fee-Farme, Fee-Taile for terme of life, liues, or yeeres, (as the Caſe ſhall require) vnto the preſent Poſſeſſors of the Inheritance: But vp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on their refuſall, or wilfull neglect of this His Maieſties intended grace, the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners to ſell any of the aforeſayd premiſſes to ſuch others as ſhall bee Suitors for the ſame: And for the Surrounded Grounds, and ſuch like, where there is no preſent Poſſeſſors, to ſuch as will compound for the ſame.</p>
            <p>And where the Tenure appeareth vpon Record, the former Tenure is to bee re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerued; But where no Tenure appeareth, there the Tenure is to be in Soccage.</p>
            <p>And <hi>Robert Typper,</hi> of Grays Inne, his Maieſties Seruant, is to attend the ſayd Commiſſioners in the execution and proſecution of the ſayd Commiſſion.</p>
            <closer>God ſaue the King.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> Imprinted at London by Bonham Norton, and Iohn Bill, Printers to the Kings moſt Excellent Maieſtie.</p>
            <p>ANNO M.DC.XXVIII.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
